PRABIN DASH

DATA SCIENTIST

0 0	
	+91 9778841064
\boxtimes	prabindash135@gmail.com
in	prabin-dash-00a281137
\bigcirc	Bangalore, India
SKILLS	
Python	
SQL	
Azure	
Tensorflow/Keras/Pytorch	
Flask/Streamlit	
NLP	
Tableau/PowerBI	
Docker	
Unix/Linux	
Git/GitHub	
EDUCATION	

CONTACT

B. Tech

College of Engineering and Technology, Bhubaneswar

2014 - 2018

Instrumentation and Electronics (8.08 GPA)

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Fundamentals

Azure Data Scientist Associate

PROFILE

Technology geek interested in exploring ML and Al domain. With 4+ years into Data Science and 2+ years working in Azure Cloud, I am interested in researching in fields such as Natural Language Processing and Generative Al. I have experience in building models as well as deploying them over Docker or Cloud platforms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

KPMG 2022-Present

- Worked for one of the biggest retail sector firm, developing a spam classification bot with language translation, embedded images etc. blockers
- Creation of raw dataset by email extraction from client mailbox using Python scripts, building various ML/DL models, deploying over Azure DevOps pipeline to Azure Web App and integration in Logic apps workflow
- Utilizing Azure tools such as Azure ML, Cognitive Services for same purpose
- Comparing all solutions by performance, efficiency and security aspects
- Reduction of manual workload by 83%
- Worked in Pharmaceutical sales domain to create Analytics Insights dashboard displaying multi-item(multiple orgs/products) Sales Forecasting and Anomaly Detection on Sales data over past timeperiod
- Extraction of raw data from SAP HANA database, copying to Azure Storage via Azure Data Factory, importing to Azure ML Studio and building models using various methods such as Automated ML
- Consuming model in PowerBI to create dashboard and setting up refresh

Data Scientist

Tata Consultancy Services

2018-2022

- Worked for one of the biggest banks in Australia, developing a Document Image Processing and intelligent text extraction project, reducing human workload by completing real time work usually done in 3-5 business days to 30 minutes
- Classifying documents using state-of-the-art algorithms(88.89%), process and extract scanned/printed text using OCR, data and document comparison using fuzzy matching and regex algorithm to highlight key differences
- Extract information from structured/unstructured texts automatically, review the
 exceptions and recommend updates in the model for improved extraction
- Deploying model into client's docker platform and integration in UI
- Worked for one of the biggest banks in Australia, in Payments domain, utilizing skills such as Python, Oracle, Unix
- Extracting huge chunks of data from Oracle database, analyzing them using Python Data Analysis tools, providing insights to clients
- Analyzing transactional processing data, implementing forecasting models to forecast weekly, monthly and quarterly expected loads, which helps reduce system downtime by 78%
- Trend Forecasting, Capacity report analysis, Dashboard preparation for monthly/quarterly processing and highlighting performance issues.
- Developing cost/benefit analysis for business solutions